Guide to the Sidney D. Gamble Photographs, 1906-2007
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- Sidney D. Gamble Foundation Records, 1919-2006, (5 boxes)
  - Miscellaneous materials about China, 1986-1995 and undated
  - Museum bookings and letters to museums about exhibition, 1989-1990
  - Photographs from exhibition in Hefei, Anhui Province, 2006
  - Photographs of exhibitions at unidentified locations
  - Photographs, Following Gamble's Footsteps, 2006
  - Photographs from exhibition at Fujian Museum, 2006
  - Photographs from exhibition at Shanxi Art Museum, 2006 and undated
  - Photographs from exhibition at Shaoxing Museum, 2006
  - Photographs from exhibition at Hohhut, Inner Mongolia Autonomous Region, 2006
  - Proposals and letters from Wayne Xing regarding an exhibition in China, 1993-1997 and undated
  - List of photographs sent to China for exhibition, 1997 and undated
  - Public relations information for exhibitions in China from Paula Webster Public Relations, 1999
  - Requests for books and permission to use Sidney D. Gamble photographs, 1995-2007 and undated, (3 folders)
  - Turbulent Years: Sidney D. Gamble's Photographs of China, an exhibition (Box 13)
    - Chengdu, 2000
    - Chongquing, 2000
    - Guangzhou, 2000
    - Hangzhou, 2000
    - Jinan, 1989-2000
    - Jinhua, 2000
    - Nanjing, 2000
    - Shanghai, 1996-1997 and undated
    - Shenzhen, 2000
    - Shijiazhuang, 2000
    - Tianjin, 2001
    - Zhengzhou, 2000
  - W. W. Norton and Company: Correspondence and catalogs, 1989-1991, 1998
  - Young Men's Christian Association (YMCA): Photocopies of annual report, 1919; and correspondence, 1925-1926, 1931
- Photographic Material Series, 1906-1992, (24 boxes)
  Photographic materials in the collection chiefly consist of several formats of the approximately 5,000 images that Gamble captured during his four sojourns in China (1908, 1917-1919, 1924-1927, and 1931-1932) and visits to other locales including Korea, Japan, Russia, Hawaii, and San Francisco. The images document urban and rural life, public events, architecture, religious statuary, and the countryside. Gamble used the images to illustrate scholarly publications and in slide lectures. Formats include contact sheets, hand-colored glass slides, duplicate slides (35mm), copy prints, a photograph album (120 contact prints), and nitrate negatives. Also included are print and card indexes to the photographs, and the original negative sleeves (with annotations).
  - Card Index to Photographs
    The card index provides access to images by location, name, and subject.
    - Card index (Box 14)
  - Contact Sheets, 1917-1932
    Contact sheets were created by the donor in the 1980s from the original nitrate negatives to serve as a reference tool for the collection. There are typically six images per contact sheet with brief descriptions of each image including the location and subject matter.
    Contact sheets are arranged by roll and exposure number
    - Photograph/slide subject index, undated (Box 15)
    - Sojourn, 1917-1919 (1A/1-3A/17)
    - Sojourn, 1917-1919 (4A/18-8A/41)
    - Sojourn, 1917-1919 (8A/42-13A/62)
    - Sojourn, 1917-1919 (13A/63-17A/84)
    - Sojourn, 1917-1919 (17A/85-20A/103)
    - Sojourn, 1917-1919 (20A/104-23A/121)
    - Sojourn, 1917-1919 (23A/122-26A/141)
    - Sojourn, 1917-1919 (27A/142-30A/161)
    - Sojourn, 1917-1919 (30A/162-33A/179)
    - Sojourn, 1917-1919 (33A/180-37A/199)
    - Sojourn, 1917-1919 (37A/200-41A/220)
    - Sojourn, 1917-1919 (41A/221-44A/242)
    - Sojourn, 1917-1919 (45A/243-47A/261)
    - Sojourn, 1917-1919 (48A/262-51A/278)
    - Sojourn, 1917-1919 (51A/279-54A/294)
    - Sojourn, 1917-1919 (55A/295-58A/314)
    - Sojourn, 1917-1919 (58A/315-61A/334)
    - Sojourn, 1917-1919 (61A/335-65A/354)
    - Sojourn, 1917-1919 (65A/355-68A/375)
    - Sojourn, 1917-1919 (69A/376-72A/395)
    - Sojourn, 1917-1919 (72A/396-75A/416)
    - Sojourn, 1917-1919 (75A/417-78A/436)
    - Sojourn, 1917-1919 (79A/437-82A/456)
    - Sojourn, 1917-1919 (82A/457-85A/476)
    - Sojourn, 1917-1919 (85A/477-89A/496)
    - Sojourn, 1917-1919 (89A/477-92A/515)
    - Sojourn, 1917-1919 (92A/516-96/535)
    - Sojourn, 1917-1919 ( 96/536-99/555)
    - Sojourn, 1917-1919 ( 99/556-102/574)
    - Sojourn, 1917-1919 ( 103/575-106/595)
    - Sojourn, 1917-1919 ( 106/594-110/614)
    - Sojourn, 1917-1919 ( 110/615-112/631)
    - Sojourn, 1917-1919 ( 112/632-116/651)
    - Sojourn, 1917-1919 ( 116/652-118/667)
    - Sojourn, 1917-1919 ( 118/667A-121/684)
    - Sojourn, 1917-1919 ( 122/686-125/706)
    - Sojourn, 1917-1919 ( 126/707-129/726)
    - Sojourn, 1917-1919 ( 129/727-132/745)
    - Sojourn, 1917-1919 (65A/355-68A/375)
    - Sojourn, 1917-1919 ( 137/746-136/765) (Box 16)
    - Sojourn, 1917-1919 (136/766-139/782)
    - Sojourn, 1917-1919 (139-783-142/801)
    - Sojourn, 1917-1919 (142/802-145/816)
    - Sojourn, 1917-1919 (145/817-148/832)
    - Sojourn, 1917-1919 (151/850-155/866)
    - Sojourn, 1917-1919 (155/867-158/886)
    - Sojourn, 1917-1919 (158/887-162/905)
    - Sojourn, 1917-1919 (162/905B-164/922)
    - Sojourn, 1917-1919 (168/942-171/961)
    - Sojourn, 1917-1919 (171/962-174/980)
    - Sojourn, 1917-1919 (175/981-178/1000)
    - Sojourn, 1917-1919 (178/1001-182/1919A)
    - Sojourn, 1917-1919 (182/1020-185/1037)
    - Sojourn, 1917-1919 (185/1038-189/1056)
    - Sojourn, 1917-1919 (189/1057-192/1075)
    - Sojourn, 1917-1919 ( 193/1076-195/1092)
    - Sojourn, 1917-1919 (195/1093-196/1098)
    - Sojourn, 1917-1919 (196/1097-199/1116)
    - Sojourn, 1917-1919 (200/1117-203/1143)
    - Sojourn, 1917-1919 (203/1135-206/1153)
    - Sojourn, 1917-1919 (207/1154-210/1171)
    - Sojourn, 1917-1919 ( 211/1172-214/1195)
    - Sojourn, 1917-1919 (214/1196-218/1215)
    - Sojourn, 1917-1919 (218/1216-221/1235)
    - Sojourn, 1917-1919 (221/1236-224/1255)
    - Sojourn, 1917-1919 (225/1256-228/1278)
    - Sojourn, 1917-1919 (228/1279-232/1301)
    - Sojourn, 1917-1919 (231/1295-235/1318)
    - Sojourn, 1917-1919 (235/1319-237/1330)
    - Sojourn, 1917-1919 (237/1331-240/1349)
    - Sojourn, 1917-1919 (240/1350-243/1366)
    - Sojourn, 1917-1919 (243/1367-246/1383)
    - Sojourn, 1917-1919 (247/1387-250/1409)
    - Sojourn, 1917-1919 (250/1406-253/1425) (Box 17)
    - Sojourn, 1917-1919 (253/1426-254/1444)
    - Sojourn, 1917-1919 (254/1445-256/1461)
    - Sojourn, 1917-1919 (256/1462-259/1479)
    - Sojourn, 1917-1919 (260/1484-263/1501)
    - Sojourn, 1917-1919 (263/1502-266/1519)
    - Sojourn, 1917-1919 (266/1520-269/1539)
    - Sojourn, 1917-1919 (269/1540-272/1557)
    - Sojourn, 1917-1919 (273/1561-275/1576)
    - Sojourn, 1917-1919 (276/1577-279/1595)
    - Sojourn, 1917-1919 (279/1596-281/1612)
    - Sojourn, 1917-1919 (282/1613-284/1628)
    - Sojourn, 1917-1919 (285/1629-287/1646)
    - Sojourn, 1917-1919 (287/1646-290/1662)
    - Sojourn, 1917-1919 (291/1663-294/1681)
    - Sojourn, 1917-1919 (294/1682-298/1704)
    - Sojourn, 1917-1919 (298/1705-301/1722)
    - Sojourn, 1917-1919 (301/1723-305/1747)
    - Sojourn, 1917-1919 (305/1748-308/1763)
    - Sojourn, 1917-1919 (308/1746-312/1783)
    - Sojourn, 1917-1919 (312/1784-313/1794)
    - Sojourn, 1919, 1924 (314/1795-312/1816)
    - Sojourn, 1919, 1924 (317/1817-321/1840)
    - Sojourn, 1919, 1924 (322/1841-326/1864)
    - Sojourn, 1919, 1924 (326/1865-330/1890)
    - Sojourn, 1919, 1924 (351/2001-354/2022)
    - Sojourn, 1919, 1924 (354/2023-359/2053)
    - Sojourn, 1919, 1924 (360/2056-363/2078)
    - Sojourn, 1919, 1924 (364/2083-369/2111)
    - Sojourn, 1919, 1924 (369/2112-373/2137)
    - Sojourn, 1919, 1924 (373/2138-377/2161)
    - Sojourn, 1919, 1924 (377/2162-383/2193) (Box 18)
    - Sojourn, 1919, 1924 (383/2194-389/2231)
    - Sojourn, 1919, 1924 (389/2232-395/2265)
    - Sojourn, 1919, 1924 (395/2266-400/2299)
    - Sojourn, 1924-1925 (400/2300-408/2344)
    - Sojourn, 1924-1925 (408/2345-415/2385)
    - Sojourn, 1924-1925 (415/2386-422/2426)
    - Sojourn, 1924-1925 (422/2427-429/2471)
    - Sojourn, 1924-1925 (430/2472-438/2518)
    - Sojourn, 1924-1925 (438/2519-445/2562)
    - Sojourn, 1924-1925 (445/2563-452/2600)
    - Sojourn, 1924-1925 (452/2601-459/2644)
    - Sojourn, 1924-1925 (459/2645-463/2671)
    - Sojourn, 1924-1925 (464/2672-468/2698)
    - Sojourn, 1925 (468/2699-274/2733)
    - Sojourn, 1925 (474/2734-481/2771)
    - Sojourn, 1925 (481/2771-487/2808)
    - Sojourn, 1925 (487/2809-492/2841)
    - Sojourn, 1925 (493/2842-497/2867)
    - Sojourn, 1925 (497/2868-502/2898)
    - Sojourn, 1925 (502/2899-508/2935)
    - Sojourn, 1925 (508/2936-514/2975) (Box 19)
    - Sojourn, 1925 (515/2976-520/3012)
    - Sojourn, 1925 (521/3013-523/3030)
    - Sojourn, 1925 (524/3032-530/3068)
    - Sojourn, 1925 (530/3069-535/3100)
    - Sojourn, 1925-1926 (536/3101-542/3140)
    - Sojourn, 1925-1926 (542/3141-549/3130)
    - Sojourn, 1925-1926 (549/3181-555/3217)
    - Sojourn, 1925-1926 (557/3226-563/3266)
    - Sojourn, 1925-1926 (563/3266-571/3311)
    - Sojourn, 1925-1926 (572/3312-579/3358)
    - Sojourn, 1925-1926 (579/3359-586/3408)
    - Sojourn, 1925-1926 (586/3410-593/3458)
    - Sojourn, 1925-1926 (594/3459-599/3497)
    - Sojourn, 1927, 1931-1932 (615/3591-623/3636)
    - Sojourn, 1927, 1931-1932 (600/3498-607/3544)
    - Sojourn, 1927, 1931-1932 (607/3544-615/3588)
    - Sojourn, 1927, 1931-1932 (623/3637-630/3683)
    - Sojourn, 1927, 1931-1932 (630/3683-638/3729)
    - Sojourn, 1927, 1931-1932 (638/3730-646/3776) (Box 20)
    - Sojourn, 1927, 1931-1932 (646/3777-653/3819)
    - Sojourn, 1927, 1931-1932 (654/3840-663/3825)
    - B-Film, 1917-1927 (1B/1-8B/66)
    - B-Film, 1917-1927 (8B/67-14B/131)
    - B-Film, 1917-1927 (14B/132-20B/197)
    - B-Film, 1917-1927 (20B/198-26B/269)
    - B-Film, 1917-1927 (26B/266-32B/333)
    - B-Film, 1917-1927 (32B/334-39B/405)
    - B-Film, 1917-1927 (39B/406-45B/475)
    - B-Film, 1917-1927 (45B/476-51B/545)
    - B-Film, 1917-1927 (51B/546-57B/616)
    - B-Film, 1917-1927 (51B/617-63B/676)
    - B-Film, 1917-1927 (63B/677-69B/747)
    - B-Film, 1917-1927 (69B/748-74B/799)
    - B-Film, 1917-1927 (74B/800-77B/843)
  - Duplicate Prints, 1917-1932
    Large (8x10) and small (2x4) photographic prints made for various publications and exhibitions of Gamble's work.
    - Contact Print Extras (Box 20)
    - Color Transparencies
    - Duplicate Prints (Large) (Box 21)
    - Select Duplicate Prints (Large and Small)
    - Duplicate prints and photocopies
    - Computerized prints
    - Duplicate prints (Box 22)
  - Duplicate Slides (35mm), 1917-1932
    Multiple sets of approximately 500 35mm duplicate slides. Each set consists of 13 small individually labeled slide cases. The 35mm slides are duplicates of selected hand-colored glass slides and black and white negatives in the collection. Also included are three small slide cases labeled test extras, containing slides of artwork and other scenes unrelated to the bulk of the collection.
    Duplicate slides are arranged numerically by exposure number. Labels on each case note the exposures in that case. Sets are distinguished by a colored dot marked on each box in that set.
    - Duplicate slides (35mm) (Box 23-24)
  - Exhibit Catalogs
    - China Between Revolutions (1989-1993) (Box 25)
    - Turbulent Years: China Before and After the May 4th Movement (1999)
    - Sidney Gamble's China Revisited (2004)
  - Glass Slides, 1906-1927
    - Glass slides: China, 1908-1927 (Box 26-34)
      Approximately 600 glass slides, mostly depicting Gamble's travels in China. The bulk of the slides are hand-colored versions of black-and-white images found elsewhere in the collection, but there are also slides featuring charts and graphs that Gamble used in his lectures and presentations on China.
      The original order of the hand-colored glass slides has been preserved. These slides were loosely arranged in alphabetical order by topic. Some slides are labeled with an exposure number and a brief description of the subject matter, while other slides contain no identifiers.
    - Glass slides: Western United States, circa 1906 (Box 35)
      Approximately 50 glass slides belonging to David Gamble, mostly depicting landscapes and other scenes in the Western United States such as: Old Faithful Geyser, the Grand Canyon, bears, and waterfalls. Also included are portraits of unidentified women.
  - Microfilm
    Microfilm of the Sidney D. Gamble Photographs, 1911-1919, held at Princeton University.
    - Microfilm (Box 24)
  - Negative sleeves
    - Original negative sleeves (with annotations) (Box 36-37)
  - Photograph Album
    - Photograph album, circa 1908 (Box 38)
      Contains 120 prints, most likely taken during Gamble's 1908 sojourn to China.
- Printed Material Series, circa 1910s-1996
  Includes mandarin character drill cards and Mandarin Readers used in the North China Union Language School, and a 1996 senior thesis on the origins and evolution of the Princeton in Asia program.
  - Character drill cards, circa 1910s (Box 39)
  - Mandarin Readers, undated, (5 envelopes)
  - Men of Faith, Men of Action: The Origins and Evolution of the Princeton in Asia Program, 1898-1937.
    A senior thesis by Andrea Yun-Woei Au, Department of History, Princeton University, 1996.
  - Card index to Sidney Gamble's private library.
- Oversize Material, 1924-2007, 1 Box
  - Preservation photocopies of Scrapbook, 1924-1929 (Box 40)
  - Articles related to China, Asia, or photography, 1982-1986
  - Chinese aphorisms with English translations, undated
  - Information and map about educational sessions in Ding county, undated
  - Special editions of newspaper Peking Ching Pao, focusing on Miao Feng Shan, 1925 May 13, 23, and 29
  - Year of the Photograph: Gamble on China; Delano's Bittersweet Harvest, Siteline, Winter 1990
  - Clippings, Shenzhen Evening News, Shenzhen Daily, and Guangzhou Morning Post, 2000 August and undated
  - Windows on the Many Chinese Revolutions, Political and Personal, The New York Times, 2004 July 2
  - Exhibition poster from the University of Cincinnati's Tangeman Fine Arts Gallery, 1990 September 18
  - Magazine and newspaper articles about China Between Revolutions exhibition, 1986-1995, (2 folders)
  - Newspaper articles related to Life in China around the May Fourth Movement, an exhibition at the Hong Kong Heritage Museum, 2003
  - Newspaper publicity related to exhibition at Changsha Museum in China, 2007 March
  - Poster, 1997 (Opaperfolder 1)